<resource xsi:schemaLocation='http://datacite.org/schema/kernel-4 http://schema.datacite.org/meta/kernel-4/metadata.xsd' xmlns:xsi='http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance' xmlns='http://datacite.org/schema/kernel-4'>
  <identifier identifierType='DOI'>10.34770/9425-b553</identifier>
  <creators>
    <creator>
      <creatorName>Wilterson, Andrew</creatorName>
      <givenName>Andrew</givenName>
      <familyName>Wilterson</familyName>
    </creator>
    <creator>
      <creatorName>Nastase, Samuel</creatorName>
      <givenName>Samuel</givenName>
      <familyName>Nastase</familyName>
    </creator>
    <creator>
      <creatorName>Bio, Branden</creatorName>
      <givenName>Branden</givenName>
      <familyName>Bio</familyName>
    </creator>
    <creator>
      <creatorName>Guterstam, Arvid</creatorName>
      <givenName>Arvid</givenName>
      <familyName>Guterstam</familyName>
    </creator>
    <creator>
      <creatorName>Graziano, Michael</creatorName>
      <givenName>Michael</givenName>
      <familyName>Graziano</familyName>
    </creator>
  </creators>
  <titles>
    <title>Attention and awareness in the dorsal attention network</title>
  </titles>
  <publisher>Princeton University</publisher>
  <resourceType resourceTypeGeneral='Dataset'/>
  <publicationYear>2020</publicationYear>
  <fundingReferences>
    <fundingReference>
      <funderName>Princeton Neuroscience Institute Innovation Fund</funderName>
      <awardNumber awardURI=''>PRINU-24400-G0002-10005089-101</awardNumber>
    </fundingReference>
  </fundingReferences>
  <relatedIdentifiers>
    <relatedIdentifier relationType='IsIdenticalTo' relatedIdentifierType='ARK'>ark:/88435/dsp01xp68kk27p</relatedIdentifier>
  </relatedIdentifiers>
  <version>1</version>
  <rightsList>
    <rights rightsURI='https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/' rightsIdentifier='CC BY'>Creative Commons Attribution 4.0 International</rights>
  </rightsList>
  <descriptions>
    <description descriptionType='Other'>
      The attention schema theory (AST) posits a specific relationship between
      subjective awareness and attention, in which awareness is the control
      model that the brain uses to aid in the endogenous control of attention.
      We proposed that the right temporoparietal junction (TPJ) is involved in
      that interaction between awareness and attention. In previous experiments,
      we developed a behavioral paradigm in human subjects to manipulate
      awareness and attention. The paradigm involved a visual cue that could be
      used to guide a shift of attention to a target stimulus. In task 1,
      subjects were aware of the visual cue, and their endogenous control
      mechanism was able to use the cue to help control attention. In task 2,
      subjects were unaware of the visual cue, and their endogenous control
      mechanism was no longer able to use it to control attention, even though
      the cue still had a measurable effect on other aspects of behavior. Here
      we tested the two tasks while scanning brain activity in human volunteers.
      We predicted that the right TPJ would be active in relation to the cue in
      task 1, but not in task 2. This prediction was confirmed. The right TPJ
      was active in relation to the cue in task 1; it was not measurably active
      in task 2; the difference was significant. In our interpretation, the
      right TPJ is involved in a complex interaction in which awareness aids in
      the control of attention. This dataset contains structural and functional
      MRI images from human subjects learning to use subliminal and superliminal
      stimuli to perform a Posner-like reaction time task. Download the
      README.txt file for a detailed description of this dataset&apos;s content
    </description>
  </descriptions>
</resource>